



Vaskar Chakma

Date of birth: 06/02/2001 | Nationality: Bangladeshi | Gender: Male | Phone

number: (+86) 17505222809 (Mobile) | **Email address:**

vaskarchakma7@gmail.com | Website: https://vaskarchakma.github.io/ | Website:

https://sites.google.com/view/vaskarchakma | Facebook:

https://www.facebook.com/home.vaskar | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vaskar-chakma/ | **WeChat:** VaskarChakma |

Whatsapp Messenger: +86 171 6648 2296 | **Skype:** +8801575034109 |

Address: Headmen Para, 1 no word, Rangamati Main Post Office, Kotwali, Rangamati., 4500, Rangamati, Bangladesh (Home)

Address: 79-505, Xingang Garden, Nantong, Jiangsu, China., 226019, Nantong, China (Work)

About me:

Currently an Undergraduate student of **Computer Science** at Nantong University. I was born and raised in Rangamati, Chittagong, Bangladesh. I did Higher Secondary in Science from Rangamati Government College. Open to higher studies and research opportunities. My research interests are *Machine learning*, *Artificial Intelligence*, and *Cyber Security*. Besides, I like to travel. I believe traveling gives you a new perspective on everything. You get to know a lot about the different cultures, the cuisines, their history, the language and all the small unique things every place has to offer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

06/01/2007 - 26/05/2008 Dighinala, Bangladesh

SCOUT LEADER BANGLADESH SCOUTS

- 1. Caring or working with young people
- 2. Managing or raising money
- 3. Sharing skills with others
- 4. Communications, media, or publicity
- 5. Learning skills in different ways

16/08/2017 - 30/12/2020 Rangamati, Bangladesh

RED CRESCENT YOUTH VOLUNTEER BANGLADESH RED CRESSCENT SOCIETY

- 1. To help those who suffer,
- 2. Without discrimination,
- 3. Whether during the conflict,
- 4. In response to natural or man-made disasters or due to conditions of chronic poverty.

Business or Sector Administrative and support service activities

Address K K Royy Street, Rangamati Main Post Office, Kotwali, Rangamati., 4500, Rangamati, Bangladesh

Email rangamati@bdrcs.org | Website www.bdrcs.org

Link https://drive.google.com/file/d/1nyVnz8j8XWkg t0Ur7kClD8bd231fvDW/view?usp=sharing



04/03/2021 - 20/01/2023 Rangamati, Bangladesh

DISTRICT AMBASSADOR BLUE TEAM BANGLADESH LTD.

- 1. Team Work
- 2. Learning Cyber Security
- 3. Penetration Testing

13/08/2021 - CURRENT Rangamati, Bangladesh

HEAD OF HUMAN RESOURCES DEVELOPMENT WING RHUVAGA

- 1. Leadership
- 2. Communications
- 3. Public dealing
- 4. Team work
- 5. Project management
- 6. Public speaking

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Dhaka, Bangladesh

HOUR OF CODE U.S. Embassy Bangladesh & Arduino Community Bangladesh

Address Dhaka, Bangladesh | Website https://bd.usembassy.gov/ |

Field of study Software and applications development and analysis

Link https://drive.google.com/file/d/1pSH0jaYs7H7flQa7z_K5ZVieHXXsrjxa/view?usp=sharing

10/2020 Bangladesh

SECURITY IN EMERGENCIES International Committee of the Red Cross - ICRC

Address Bangladesh | Website www.ifrc.org | Field of study Health and welfare

Link https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Xq6Tcsbt1hnmDYDP-IMX5Xw7-M5ALa-E/view?usp=sharing

07/2021 Bangladesh

VOLUNTEERISM FOR SOCIAL CHANGE Bangladesh Youth Leadership Center (BYLC)

Address Bangladesh | Website https://bylc.org/ | Field of study Personal skills and development

Link https://x.bylc.org/slides/volunteerism-for-social-change-105

07/08/2021 United States

PROTECT AGAINST SECURITY THREATS ON AZURE Microsoft

Address United States | Website https://learn.microsoft.com/

Field of study Information and Communication Technologies

Link https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/training/achievements/learn.azure.protect-against-security-threats-azure.badge?username=VaskarChakma-1649&sharingId=4C33B906947E29DC

31/01/2022 - CURRENT Bangladesh

PROBLEM SOLVING (BASIC) HackerRank

Address Bangladesh | Website https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/eadf59aa54a0



13/02/2022

ETHICAL HACKING: COMPLETE NMAP COURSE | PROJECT BASE Udemy

Website https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-40915612-141b-4c12-aca6-36a92a09c6da/

2022 Rangamati, Bangladesh

DIGITAL KHICHURI CHALLENGE United Nations Development Programme, Bangladesh

Address Moanoghar Residential School, Rangamati Main Post Office, Kotwali, Rangamati., Rangamati, Bangladesh

Field of study Inter-disciplinary programmes and qualifications involving Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs)

Link https://drive.google.com/file/d/10eb00ycE0VudANo_BJSPrl9dXtpj3Jwd/view?usp=sharing

15/09/2021 - CURRENT Nantong, China

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE Nantong University

Address No- 9, Seyuan Road, Nantong, Jiangsu, China., Nantong, China | Website http://sie.ntu.edu.cn/

Field of study Computer Science and Technology

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): CHAKMA

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
BENGALI	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
ENGLISH	B2	B2	B2	В2	B2
CHINESE	B1	A2	В1	B1	A2
HINDI	В1	B1	A2	A2	B1
URDU	B1	A1	A2	A2	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Python Programming | Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel) | Web Development + Web Design | SEO | Social Media | Google (Google Meet, Google Docs, Google Classroom, Google Forms, Google Drive, Google Slides) | C/C++ Programming